<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://www.dailyssrn.com">
<title>DailySSRN - A</title>
<link>http://www.dailyssrn.com</link>
<description>Summary of new papers published on SSRN over the last day</description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>publisher person</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2012-08-01T00:00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134822" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2133960" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134822" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134186" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134822">
<title>Estimation of the Investment Function in Sudan (1979-2008)</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134822</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1389026&#x22;&#x3E;Issam A.W. Mohamed&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;Most developing and underdeveloped countries beside Sudan suffer from low levels of income in addition to the low savings that are result from the lack of sophisticatd savings channels. Hence, investments depend on the individuals&#x26;#x27; abilities on savings where they are major motivating vehicle for economic activity due to its direct correlation with capital accumulation process that increases the productive capacity for the national economy and help to create job opportunities and achieving economic development. Subsequently, the importance of the investment comes from the effective role that can be practiced on the national product. Currently, Sudan endures severe economic crisis which the degeneration of its economic sectors, subsequent deteriorating productivity and diminishing revenues specially after the secession of the Southern region and loss of more than 75% of oil resources. The needs for investments escalate to revive its ability to survive, without that can be mission impossible. This study aims at explaining the impact of influencing factors on the investment function in the Sudan. An econometric model is formulated, assuming that there is a causal relationship between investment and influential factors represented. The results show there is a positive relationship between investment and Gross Domestic Products (GDP), while there is a negative relationship between inflation rate and finance cost on investment. The study concluded that there is significant effect of the inflation rate and finance cost. However, there are other factors that may have negative impacts on investments which can vary from administrative complications to corruption that are rife and probably entrenched in the system. From the above mentioned results the study recommends that it is necessary to extend the analysis to include other variables with significant effect on investment such as imports, national income, and government expenditure to attain a model that can be used for investment anticipation in the coming years. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2133960">
<title>Does Social Interaction Destablise Financial Markets?</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2133960</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=945565&#x22;&#x3E;Frederik K&#xF6;nig&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;With this paper, I propose a simple asset pricing model that accounts for the influence from social interaction. Investors are assumed to make up their mind about an asset&#x26;#x2019;s price based on a forecasting strategy and its past profitability as well as on the contemporaneous expectations of other market participants. Empirically analysing stocks of the DAX30 index, I provide evidence that social interaction rather destabilises financial markets. Based on my results, I state that at least, it does not have a stabilising effect. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134822">
<title>Estimation of the Investment Function in Sudan (1979-2008)</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134822</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1389026&#x22;&#x3E;Issam A.W. Mohamed&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;Most developing and underdeveloped countries beside Sudan suffer from low levels of income in addition to the low savings that are result from the lack of sophisticatd savings channels. Hence, investments depend on the individuals&#x26;#x27; abilities on savings where they are major motivating vehicle for economic activity due to its direct correlation with capital accumulation process that increases the productive capacity for the national economy and help to create job opportunities and achieving economic development. Subsequently, the importance of the investment comes from the effective role that can be practiced on the national product. Currently, Sudan endures severe economic crisis which the degeneration of its economic sectors, subsequent deteriorating productivity and diminishing revenues specially after the secession of the Southern region and loss of more than 75% of oil resources. The needs for investments escalate to revive its ability to survive, without that can be mission impossible. This study aims at explaining the impact of influencing factors on the investment function in the Sudan. An econometric model is formulated, assuming that there is a causal relationship between investment and influential factors represented. The results show there is a positive relationship between investment and Gross Domestic Products (GDP), while there is a negative relationship between inflation rate and finance cost on investment. The study concluded that there is significant effect of the inflation rate and finance cost. However, there are other factors that may have negative impacts on investments which can vary from administrative complications to corruption that are rife and probably entrenched in the system. From the above mentioned results the study recommends that it is necessary to extend the analysis to include other variables with significant effect on investment such as imports, national income, and government expenditure to attain a model that can be used for investment anticipation in the coming years. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134186">
<title>Examining Our Food Consumption Practices for Better Health and Well-Being</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134186</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1884976&#x22;&#x3E;Dawn Hellier&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;Obesity is a global epidemic and despite being a major leading cause of death and disease, is not viewed to be as perilous and critical as other epidemics such as cholera, dengue fever or West Nile virus. Excessive and unhealthy consumption practices are killing people and costing millions of dollars in the health care industry. While it is recognized that the causes of this epidemic are perhaps far more complex than other health crises, the solutions that have been identified are limited in focus and fail to consider the comprehensive nature of the issue. While beneficial, it is not enough to increase fruit and vegetable intake or physical activity. A review of research on food practices is revealing of some of the factors that are leading to our excess baggage but the studies tend to be concentrated on singular influences without placing the consumption behaviors into context with the other contributors to this condition. Certainly, research on increases in portion or serving sizes, consumer behavior patterns, social, technological and other lifestyle influences on eating, as well as food source and quality, labeling, packaging and distribution are all extremely relevant. However, effectively addressing the obesity issue demands an examination and understanding of how, when, where, why and what people eat. Until there is a commitment to a more universal multi-disciplinary approach to this societal affliction, we will continue to be tipping the scale toward a gluttonous and malignant existence. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>