<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://www.dailyssrn.com">
<title>DailySSRN - F</title>
<link>http://www.dailyssrn.com</link>
<description>Summary of new papers published on SSRN over the last day</description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>publisher person</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2012-08-01T00:00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2133841" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134932" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134696" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2135321" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134857" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134961" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134585" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2135097" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2135300" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134681" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2135300" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134696" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134682" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134857" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2133959" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134772" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134682" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134961" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2133841">
<title>Do Poor Quality Institutions Attract Mergers and Acquisitions?</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2133841</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=804330&#x22;&#x3E;Poonam Singh&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;Quality of institutions has been found to positively affect Foreign Direct Investment (FDI) flows. This, however, fails to explain the flow of FDI into countries with poor quality of institutions like India and China. This paper shows that FDI flows in the form of cross border mergers and acquisitions (CBMAs) in India share a negative relationship with the gap in quality of institutions between the host and home countries after controlling for market size and market opportunity in the home and host country and infrastructural facilities in the host country. This suggests that apart from market size and opportunity, CBMAs in India are attracted by poor quality of institutions, particularly corruption and poor governance in the country. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134932">
<title>The Law of Cyber-Attack</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134932</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=240242&#x22;&#x3E;Oona A. Hathaway&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=602148&#x22;&#x3E;William Perdue&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1553979&#x22;&#x3E;Philip Levitz&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1592192&#x22;&#x3E;Aileen Elizabeth Nowlan&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1640196&#x22;&#x3E;Rebecca Crootof&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1885987&#x22;&#x3E;Haley Nix&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1885990&#x22;&#x3E;Julia Spiegel&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;Cyber-attacks have become increasingly common in recent years. Capable of shutting down nuclear centrifuges, air defense systems, and electrical grids, cyber-attacks pose a serious threat to national security. As a result, some have suggested that cyber-attacks should be treated as acts of war. Yet the attacks look little like the armed attacks that the law of war has traditionally regulated. This Article examines how existing law may be applied &#x26;#x2014; and adapted and amended &#x26;#x2014; to meet the distinctive challenge posed by cyber-attacks. It begins by clarifying what cyber-attacks are and how they already are regulated by existing bodies of law, including the law of war, international treaties, and domestic criminal law. This review makes clear that existing law effectively addresses only a small fraction of potential cyber-attacks. The law of war, for example, provides a useful framework for only the very small number of cyber-attacks that amount to an armed attack or that take place in the context of an ongoing armed conflict. This Article concludes that a new, comprehensive legal framework at both the domestic and international levels is needed to more effectively address cyber-attacks. The United States could strengthen its domestic law by giving domestic criminal laws addressing cyber-attacks extra-territorial effect and by adopting limited, internationally permissible countermeasures to combat cyber-attacks that do not rise to the level of armed attacks or that do not take place during an ongoing armed conflict. Yet the challenge cannot be met by domestic reforms alone. International cooperation will be essential to a truly effective legal response. New international efforts to regulate cyber-attacks must begin with agreement on the problem &#x26;#x2014; which means agreement on the definition of cyber-attack, cyber-crime, and cyber-warfare. This would form the foundation for greater international cooperation on information sharing, evidence collection, and criminal prosecution of those involved in cyber-attacks &#x26;#x2014; in short, for a new international law of cyber-attack. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134696">
<title>Export Market Dynamics and Plant&#x2010;Level Productivity: Impact of Tariff Reductions and Exchange&#x2010;Rate Cycles</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134696</link>
<description>Paywalled paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=55716&#x22;&#x3E;John R. Baldwin&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=700036&#x22;&#x3E;Beiling Yan&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;In this paper, we examine how changes in tariff rates and industry&#x26;#x2010;specific real exchange rates affect the entry/exit process to export markets and productivity growth. Using the experience of the Canadian manufacturing sector over three decades, we find that firms in export markets enjoy faster productivity growth than non&#x26;#x2010;participants. The size of the growth advantage depends on whether real exchange rates are increasing or decreasing. The increase in the value of the Canadian dollar during the post&#x26;#x2010;2000 period almost completely offset the productivity growth advantages enjoyed by new exporters during this period. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2135321">
<title>Auto Sector Impacts of a Canada-Japan Free Trade Agreement: A Market-Segment-Based Evaluation</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2135321</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1316940&#x22;&#x3E;Dan Ciuriak&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;With the recent completion of a second Joint Study regarding a Canada-Japan Free Trade Agreement, and Canada&#x26;#x2019;s entry into the Trans-Pacific Partnership negotiations, which may eventually include Japan, the implications of trade liberalization with Asian economies gains renewed interest, in particular the implications for Canada&#x26;#x2019;s auto sector, which has been a stumbling block in previous negotiations. This paper considers the implications of auto sector liberalization between Canada and Japan. The impacts are modest for three main reasons: the export-orientation of Canada&#x26;#x2019;s auto sector, the fact that auto manufacturers price strategically, often practicing &#x26;#x201C;pricing to market&#x26;#x201D; (PTM) and so do not automatically pass on tariff cuts to consumers, and the impact of tariff cuts at the border is muted by the large share of domestic transport and distribution costs in the final consumer price. Taking into account the segmented nature of the auto sector tends to amplify rather than reduce the scale of the effects on the Canadian industry, suggesting that there is some degree of aggregation bias in analyses that treat the sector in aggregated terms. Income effects from the overall CJFTA would be expected to be channelled in part into increased auto purchases, providing a sizeable offset to the direct negative trade effects. Based on previous estimates of income gains from a CJFTA, this would reduce the negative impacts on Canadian production by half. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134857">
<title>Credit Constraints, Quality, and Export Prices: Theory and Evidence from China</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134857</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=296598&#x22;&#x3E;Edwin L.C. Lai&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=986162&#x22;&#x3E;Yao Amber Li&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1748149&#x22;&#x3E;Haichao Fan&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;This paper examines (i) the relationship between the credit constraints faced by a firm and the unit value prices of its exports, as well as (ii) the relationship between the export prices of a firm and its productivity. The paper extends Melitz&#x26;#x27;s (2003) model of trade with heterogeneous firms by introducing endogenous quality, credit constraints and marketing costs. There are three key findings. First, there exists a positive relationship between firm productivity and export prices because the choice of higher-quality inputs is associated with higher productivity. Second, tighter credit constraints faced by a firm reduces its optimal prices as its choice of lower-quality inputs dominates the price distortion effect resulting from credit constraints. Third, if one adopts the alternative assumption that quality is exogenous across firms, then completely opposite results would be expected: there would be a negative relationship between prices and productivity; prices increase as firms face tighter credit constraints. An empirical analysis using Chinese bank loans data, Chinese firm-level data from the National Bureau of Statistics of China (NBSC), and Chinese customs data strongly supports the predictions of the endogenous-quality model, and confirms the existence of the quality adjustment effect: firms optimally choose lower quality when facing tighter credit constraints. Our finding of a significant impact of credit constraints on export prices indicates the prevalence of heterogeneity of product quality across firms. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134961">
<title>Impacts of Intermediate Trade on Structural Change</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134961</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=132909&#x22;&#x3E;Helmut Wagner&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1636491&#x22;&#x3E;Denis Stijepic&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;Traditional structural change theories study the dynamics of inter-sector labour-reallocation in autarky models. We analyse how model-results change if open economy setting is assumed, where we focus on the impacts of intermediate trade in a multi-sector growth model with capital accumulation. We show that, when controlling for specialisation-effects, open economy features a relatively high employment share of capital/manufacturing sector and a relatively low rate of labour-reallocation across consumption industries in comparison to autarky. The process of tertiarisation (transition to a services economy) is relatively slow in the intermediate trade model in comparison to the autarky model. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134585">
<title>Japan&#x2019;s Post-Triple-Disaster Growth Strategy</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134585</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=430557&#x22;&#x3E;Masahiro Kawai&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=450658&#x22;&#x3E;Peter Morgan&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;The repercussions of the Great East Japan Earthquake on 11 March 2011 spread far beyond the geographical areas directly affected. The disaster also highlighted Japan&#x26;#x2019;s many other structural challenges besides reconstruction needs, including persistently low growth, population aging and low fertility, burgeoning government debt, declining international competitiveness, and uncertain energy supplies. Moreover, the global financial crisis and the ongoing euro area financial crisis suggest that Japan needs to create its own growth momentum without relying excessively on markets in the United States (US) and Europe. This paper discusses the scope of these challenges and sets out a long-term strategy for overcoming them and putting the Japanese economy on a stable growth path. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2135097">
<title>Legislated Protection and the WTO</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2135097</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=711600&#x22;&#x3E;T. Renee Bowen&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;Tariff bindings and administered protection are two characteristics of the WTO that are little understood. Tariff bindings place a ceiling on tariffs that is not always reached, while administered protection ensures that all sectors have access to some minimum import protection, effectively creating a floor for protection. How do these policies affect applied MFN tariff rates that are enacted through the legislature? More specifically, can these policies embolden legislatures to enact lower applied tariffs? I address this question using a model of tariffs determined by a dynamic legislative process. I show existence of a set of symmetric Markov perfect equilibria in which a low level of protection is a possible outcome, and show that it is more difficult to achieve this outcome with tariff bindings and easier to achieve with administered protection, than it is under purely legislated protection. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2135300">
<title>Vertical Gravity</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2135300</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=364375&#x22;&#x3E;Benno Ferrarini&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=535809&#x22;&#x3E;Douglas Brooks&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;We use a newly developed indicator of production sharing and processing trade to investigate the determinants of such trade in the context of a gravity model. The Network Trade Index measures countries&#x26;#x2019; interdependence through the extent of trade in parts and components for further processing and assembly of final exports goods. The intensity of processing trade among 75 countries between 1998 and 2005 is then assessed against the typical gravity determinants of trade, such as distance and joint income, jointly with bilateral foreign direct investment stocks and trade policy measures, such as applied bilateral tariff levels and the existence of preferential trade agreements. We find that trade policy plays a significant role in facilitating the intensity of production sharing and vertical trade. Joint adherence to a preferential trade agreement increases processing trade substantially, and a fall of 10% in average applied tariffs is estimated to increase vertical trade integration by 6.2% on average. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134681">
<title>Exploring the Existence of Local and Global Knowledge Spillovers: Evidence from Plant-Level Data</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134681</link>
<description>Paywalled paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=92602&#x22;&#x3E;Luisito Bertinelli&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1885741&#x22;&#x3E;Andreas Heinen&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2135300">
<title>Vertical Gravity</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2135300</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=364375&#x22;&#x3E;Benno Ferrarini&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=535809&#x22;&#x3E;Douglas Brooks&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;We use a newly developed indicator of production sharing and processing trade to investigate the determinants of such trade in the context of a gravity model. The Network Trade Index measures countries&#x26;#x2019; interdependence through the extent of trade in parts and components for further processing and assembly of final exports goods. The intensity of processing trade among 75 countries between 1998 and 2005 is then assessed against the typical gravity determinants of trade, such as distance and joint income, jointly with bilateral foreign direct investment stocks and trade policy measures, such as applied bilateral tariff levels and the existence of preferential trade agreements. We find that trade policy plays a significant role in facilitating the intensity of production sharing and vertical trade. Joint adherence to a preferential trade agreement increases processing trade substantially, and a fall of 10% in average applied tariffs is estimated to increase vertical trade integration by 6.2% on average. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134696">
<title>Export Market Dynamics and Plant&#x2010;Level Productivity: Impact of Tariff Reductions and Exchange&#x2010;Rate Cycles</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134696</link>
<description>Paywalled paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=55716&#x22;&#x3E;John R. Baldwin&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=700036&#x22;&#x3E;Beiling Yan&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;In this paper, we examine how changes in tariff rates and industry&#x26;#x2010;specific real exchange rates affect the entry/exit process to export markets and productivity growth. Using the experience of the Canadian manufacturing sector over three decades, we find that firms in export markets enjoy faster productivity growth than non&#x26;#x2010;participants. The size of the growth advantage depends on whether real exchange rates are increasing or decreasing. The increase in the value of the Canadian dollar during the post&#x26;#x2010;2000 period almost completely offset the productivity growth advantages enjoyed by new exporters during this period. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134682">
<title>Exchange Rates and Long&#x2010;Term Bonds</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134682</link>
<description>Paywalled paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=54400&#x22;&#x3E;Annika Alexius&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=153430&#x22;&#x3E;Peter Sellin&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;There is tentative evidence to suggest that the well&#x26;#x2010;documented empirical failure of uncovered interest parity (UIP) is confined to short&#x26;#x2010;term interest rates. However, tests of UIP for long&#x26;#x2010;term bonds are thwarted by various data problems. These data problems can be avoided by focusing on short investments in long&#x26;#x2010;term bonds. This paper concerns the relationship between changes in the US dollar&#x26;#x2013;Deutsche Mark exchange rate and returns to short investments in US and German long&#x26;#x2010;term government bonds. The hypothesis that expected returns to investments in bonds denominated in the two currencies are equal is not rejected, and the estimated slope coefficients are positive. For corresponding short&#x26;#x2010;term interest rates, the typical finding of negative and large Fama coefficients is confirmed. We conclude that it is the maturity of the asset, rather than the investment horizon, that matters for the results. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134857">
<title>Credit Constraints, Quality, and Export Prices: Theory and Evidence from China</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134857</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=296598&#x22;&#x3E;Edwin L.C. Lai&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=986162&#x22;&#x3E;Yao Amber Li&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1748149&#x22;&#x3E;Haichao Fan&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;This paper examines (i) the relationship between the credit constraints faced by a firm and the unit value prices of its exports, as well as (ii) the relationship between the export prices of a firm and its productivity. The paper extends Melitz&#x26;#x27;s (2003) model of trade with heterogeneous firms by introducing endogenous quality, credit constraints and marketing costs. There are three key findings. First, there exists a positive relationship between firm productivity and export prices because the choice of higher-quality inputs is associated with higher productivity. Second, tighter credit constraints faced by a firm reduces its optimal prices as its choice of lower-quality inputs dominates the price distortion effect resulting from credit constraints. Third, if one adopts the alternative assumption that quality is exogenous across firms, then completely opposite results would be expected: there would be a negative relationship between prices and productivity; prices increase as firms face tighter credit constraints. An empirical analysis using Chinese bank loans data, Chinese firm-level data from the National Bureau of Statistics of China (NBSC), and Chinese customs data strongly supports the predictions of the endogenous-quality model, and confirms the existence of the quality adjustment effect: firms optimally choose lower quality when facing tighter credit constraints. Our finding of a significant impact of credit constraints on export prices indicates the prevalence of heterogeneity of product quality across firms. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2133959">
<title>The PIIGS Stock Markets Before and After the 2008 Financial Crisis: A Dynamic Cointegration and Causality Analysis</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2133959</link>
<description>Abstract only by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=406881&#x22;&#x3E;Dimitris Kenourgios&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=931393&#x22;&#x3E;Petros Kalantonis&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=969467&#x22;&#x3E;Apostolos G. Christopoulos&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1659060&#x22;&#x3E;Andreas S. Chouliaras&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;This paper investigates whether cointegration and causality relationships exist among the stock markets of the PIIGS countries (Portugal, Italy, Ireland, Greece and Spain) during the period 2005-2011. To accomplish our objective, we divide the sample period into two sub-periods (1 February 2005-30 June 2008 and 1 July 2008-30 June 2011). Considering that the financial crisis, which initiated in the USA in 2007, expanded to the EU in mid-2008, we call the first period &#x26;#x201C;pre-crisis period&#x26;#x201D; and the second &#x26;#x201C;crisis period&#x26;#x201D;. We apply a battery of tests such as Johansen cointegration, Granger causality, Gregory and Hansen residuals cointegration with regime shifts, fully modified ordinary least squares, as well as a multivariate GARCH model. Conventional cointegration and vector error correction analysis show long and short run dynamics among PIIGS markets, especially during the crisis period. Further analysis into a regime switching and GARCH framework confirms the existence of cointegrating relationships among these stock markets while there are volatility spillovers between Greece and the rest of the countries. The findings have important implications for portfolio diversification benefits and the systemic nature of the crisis within the PIIGS countries. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134772">
<title>Types of Foreign Aid</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134772</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=341059&#x22;&#x3E;Christian Bj&#xF8;rnskov&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;Foreign aid is given for many purposes and different intentions, yet most studies treat aid flows as a unitary concept. This paper uses factor analysis to separate aid flows into different types. The main types can be interpreted as aid for economic purposes, social purposes, and reconstruction; a residual category captures remaining purposes. Estimating the growth effects of separable types of aid suggests that most aid has no effects while reconstruction aid has direct positive effects. Although this type only applies in special circumstances, it has become more prevalent in more recent years. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134682">
<title>Exchange Rates and Long&#x2010;Term Bonds</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134682</link>
<description>Paywalled paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=54400&#x22;&#x3E;Annika Alexius&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=153430&#x22;&#x3E;Peter Sellin&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;There is tentative evidence to suggest that the well&#x26;#x2010;documented empirical failure of uncovered interest parity (UIP) is confined to short&#x26;#x2010;term interest rates. However, tests of UIP for long&#x26;#x2010;term bonds are thwarted by various data problems. These data problems can be avoided by focusing on short investments in long&#x26;#x2010;term bonds. This paper concerns the relationship between changes in the US dollar&#x26;#x2013;Deutsche Mark exchange rate and returns to short investments in US and German long&#x26;#x2010;term government bonds. The hypothesis that expected returns to investments in bonds denominated in the two currencies are equal is not rejected, and the estimated slope coefficients are positive. For corresponding short&#x26;#x2010;term interest rates, the typical finding of negative and large Fama coefficients is confirmed. We conclude that it is the maturity of the asset, rather than the investment horizon, that matters for the results. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134961">
<title>Impacts of Intermediate Trade on Structural Change</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134961</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=132909&#x22;&#x3E;Helmut Wagner&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1636491&#x22;&#x3E;Denis Stijepic&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;Traditional structural change theories study the dynamics of inter-sector labour-reallocation in autarky models. We analyse how model-results change if open economy setting is assumed, where we focus on the impacts of intermediate trade in a multi-sector growth model with capital accumulation. We show that, when controlling for specialisation-effects, open economy features a relatively high employment share of capital/manufacturing sector and a relatively low rate of labour-reallocation across consumption industries in comparison to autarky. The process of tertiarisation (transition to a services economy) is relatively slow in the intermediate trade model in comparison to the autarky model. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>