<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rss version="2.0"
 xmlns:blogChannel="http://backend.userland.com/blogChannelModule"
>

<channel>
<title>DailySSRN - M</title>
<link>http://www.dailyssrn.com</link>
<description>Summary of new papers published on SSRN over the last day</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>720</ttl>

<item>
<title>Privatizaci&#xF3;n y Eficiencia Productiva: An&#xE1;lisis del caso Ensidesa/CSI/Aceralia (Privatisation and Productive Efficiency: A Case Study: Aceralia)</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2129676</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1051086&#x22;&#x3E;Maria Teresa Bosch&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1217564&#x22;&#x3E;Joaquim Verg&#xE9;s&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;Este trabajo se enmarca en los an&#x26;#xE1;lisis de los cambios producidos en la eficiencia productiva de una empresa p&#x26;#xFA;blica cuando &#x26;#xE9;sta se privatiza, en el sentido de que su control efectivo pasa a manos de inversores privados. El caso concreto de estudio aqu&#x26;#xED; es la empresa Ensidesa, que posteriormente nucle&#x26;#xF3; el Grupo CSI, luego reestructurado y privatizado bajo el nombre de Aceralia. El  estudio utiliza diferentes indicadores de eficiencia, tanto econ&#x26;#xF3;mico-financieros como de productividad.  Los resultados muestran que la fase previa a la privatizaci&#x26;#xF3;n es el momento en que se producen los cambios significativos en las tendencias de los distintos indicadores relacionados con la eficiencia, produci&#x26;#xE9;ndose una mejor&#x26;#xED;a sustancial en estos; y que estos niveles de eficiencia simplemente se mantiene en la fase posterior a la privatizaci&#x26;#xF3;n. Esta evidencia emp&#x26;#xED;rica, paralela a la de otras investigaciones, no da soporte a la tesis habitual sobre privatizaci&#x26;#xF3;n/eficiencia derivada de la teoria de los derechos de propiedad,  lo que sugiere la conveniencia de acumular m&#x26;#xE1;s evidencia emp&#x26;#xED;rica al respecto.   This article presents an analysis on the changes in productive efficiency when a public owned enterprise is privatized, in the sense that the firm&#x26;#x2019;s control passes to private investors. The case under study is the long-standing State-owned Spanish iron and steel firm Ensidesa, which in the 90&#x26;#x2019;s became the core of the CSI group, which, in turn, was restructured afterwards and then privatized under the name of Aceralia. The study uses several efficiency measures, either financial and productivity indicators.   The main finding is that it was in the years previous to privatization where our efficiency analysis shows a relevant improvement by all efficiency measures; and that these levels of efficiency remained rather unchanged after the privatization of the firm. Thus, our empirical results do not lend support to the standard proposition of the property rights theory about that privatization will yield an increase in firm&#x26;#x2019;s efficiency. This finding is similar to some other previous studies&#x26;#x2019; on privatizations of public enterprises, which suggest that more empirical evidence on this subject should be useful. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dynamic Properties of Earnings in the Bond Market</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134547</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1379640&#x22;&#x3E;Thomas R. Loy&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1885705&#x22;&#x3E;Ronny K. Hofmann&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;This study extends recent accounting research in the corporate debt market by incorporating a dynamic element into investment decision frameworks that is linked to the recent financial crisis. Controlling for the presence of systematic risk and private information of credit rating agencies, we provide evidence that accounting accruals and cash flows are not associated with corporate bond returns in the three years preceding the financial crisis. However, using a point estimate of the conditional mean of annual bond returns, we find a positive and significant association of accounting accruals with annual bond returns during the recent financial crisis. Additionally, using a semi-parametric technique to include conditional quantiles of bond returns, we show that the rate of change in the regression coefficients is dependent on those quantiles. Thus, we provide evidence that, conditional on the distribution of bond returns, both changes in cash flows and accruals are positively and significantly associated with annual bond returns during the recent financial crisis. Our results suggest that debt market investors base their investment decisions on credible market-based measures during the prefinancial crisis, but complement these information signals with accounting-based measures during the recent financial crisis. Therefore, accounting signals may reflect information about a firm&#x26;#x2019;s closeness to default and creditworthiness that is not captured by market-based measures. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Making Causal Inferences in Small Samples Using Synthetic Control Methodology: Did Chrysler Benefit from Government Assistance?</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2135294</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=329200&#x22;&#x3E;Guy L. F. Holburn&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=589775&#x22;&#x3E;Brian Kelleher Richter&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1382777&#x22;&#x3E;Adam Fremeth&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;We introduce to management research a recently developed statistical methodology &#x26;#x2013; synthetic control.  The method overcomes challenges to causal inference in contexts constrained by small samples or few occurrences of the phenomenon of interest.  Synthetic control constructs a replica of a focal firm, or other observation unit, based on a weighted combination of unaffected firms with similar attributes within the sample population. The method quantifies the magnitude and direction of a treatment effect by comparing the actual performance of a focal unit to its counterfactual replica without treatment. We demonstrate its utility to management researchers by applying it to Chrysler&#x26;#x2019;s 2008 decision to accept conditional government assistance.  Our synthetic control analysis shows that Chrysler, or its surviving components, would have sold approximately 20% more vehicles in the U.S. through summer 2011 had the company instead relied on private financing and market forces. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Eco-Management in Polish Companies</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2133996</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1885359&#x22;&#x3E;Ewa Bojar&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;Economic activity has an enormous influence on the  environment. Enterprises contribute to the progressing degradation of existing ecosystems, cause serious threats to the biological diversity of our planet, emit hazardous pollutants and use available natural resources excessively, which can lead to their premature exhaustion. Therefore, for the world&#x26;#x2019;s nations to grow and develop in a sustainable manner, there is an urgent need to minimize the adverse impact of business activities, households and whole societies on the environment. Environmental degradation  cannot be restrained by the neutralization of produced pollutants alone. Today, we need efficient environment-friendly technologies and production processes. Effective efforts aimed at the reduction of our ecological footprint should be undertaken by all  involved entities, including designers, engineers and managers at all stages of the product design, production and distribution processes. The concept of corporate social responsibility, understood as a voluntary process of taking into account a wide array of social and ecological issues in all business activities as well as contacts with stakeholders, has become very popular in Poland. Development of the concept of corporate social responsibility (CSR) and sustainable development has a huge impact on the shaping of pro-ecological attitudes in society. From this perspective corporate social responsibility (CSR) can be rightly regarded as a concept useful to ensure sustainable development at the micro-level, i.e. at the level of enterprises. CSR is a component of sustainable eco-management. It can ensure that the principles of sustainable development are effectively implemented at the level of  socio-economic  systems, as well as individual  actors involved in change.  Lublin Voivodeship has a clean and attractive environment. This paper presents research findings of the study carried out in 2005-2010 by researchers from the Faculty of Management, Lublin University of Technology. The main purpose of the study was to analyze the environmental activities and initiatives undertaken by enterprises operating in the region, directions of pro-environmental investments, implemented environmental management systems, as well as motivations of business managers to pay more attention to environmental issues. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ecosystem Services in the Light of a Sustainable Knowledge-Based Economy</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2133970</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1885352&#x22;&#x3E;Artur Micha&#x142;owski&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;The article attempts to present the issue of ecosystem  services in the light of a sustainable knowledge-based economy. The category of ecosystem services is of key importance in the emerging economy of sustainable development, which analyses the society-economy-environment macro-system. The economic system should be based on knowledge and pursue a new paradigm of sustainable development, with consideration given to ecosystem services. The article examines the most important aspects of sustainable development and the essence of a sustainable knowledge-based economy as theoretical and practical perspectives of outlining the foundations of ecosystem services for the development of society. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>HRD Practices and Philosophy of Management in Indian Organization</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134068</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1872078&#x22;&#x3E;Anil Kumar Singh&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;The  managerial philosophy of  a  company is  generally  based   upon  the  top  management&#x26;#x2019;s assumptions  about people  working in the organization. It reflects the attitude of the top manage-  ment towards the human resources of an organization. Managerial philosophies of companies are embedded in the society. McGregor (1960) has labelled these managerial philosophies as &#x26;#x2018;Theory X and Theory Y.&#x26;#x2019;This paper is an attempt to identify the relationship between human resource (HR) practices and the philosophy of management of the Indian business organizations. For this, the different variables of HR practices were studied and the management&#x26;#x2019;s philosophy was identified by measuring beliefs of top management about employees  in the organizations.  The sample for the study consisted  of 95 respondents from two private sector organizations and 119 respondents from two public sector organizations.The findings of the study indicate that the variables of HR practices (planning, recruitment, and selection) were highly but negatively related to the philosophy of management in the private sector organizations.  This meant that the Indian organizations were practising traditional philosophy of management in such organizations. The prevalence of traditional managerial philosophy focusing on managerial control has always dominated the managerial community in the sense that it is more prevalent and is more &#x26;#x2018;tightly&#x26;#x2019; linked to managerial practice. As new managerial ideologies evolved, the older ones &#x26;#x201C;never disappeared; instead,  images and practices central to each were gradually institutionalized&#x26;#x201D; (Barley and Kunda, 1992).The philosophy of management showed  a blurred picture in the public sector organizations. Though the top management&#x26;#x2019;s views and balance sheet emphasized the belief of the organization towards  Theory Y, the analysed  responses  proved  that management philosophy was not clear to managers working in these organizations.In fact, the Indian public sector organizations started as welfare organizations. However,  the impact  of market  economy has  led  to a competitive environment.  Though  the  public  sector organizations have started realizing the impact of competition, it is difficult for them to understand when they lost their focus on the managerial philosophy.The following key issues emerged  from the study: Organizations will have  to design  managerial The managerial philosophy in the organization has an impact on the organizations of the future.HR concepts that get packaged along with modern  managerial philosophy are likely to revolutionize the workplace. The bottom line is that people  want to be cared for and respected.On their part, organizations want commitment and integrity. A successful  combination of committed  people  and a benevolent organization could well be the way for organizations in this competitive environment in India. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Man and Nature - A New Project on New Spirituality</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2133957</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1885333&#x22;&#x3E;Zbigniew Pasek&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;This article is a prelude to a planned project aimed at researching new ways of understanding and redefining the concept of nature in the so-called New Spirituality movements. The authors begin from a theoretical  context associated with the meaning, for religious studies, of the sacred &#x26;#x2013; profane and culture &#x26;#x2013; nature dichotomies, and show the changes religiousness undergoes. Today we see an increasing number of people turning away from traditional forms of religious  cult with a simultaneously declared wish to develop their own spirituality. New spirituality is provisionally defined here as the worldly transgression of the human condition committed in the name of different values strongly associated with the physical (bodily) dimension of life and a holistic vision of the world. On the basis of examples, drawn mainly from publications based on the Deep Ecology trend, the authors discuss three aspects: (1) a new understanding of one&#x26;#x2019;s own nature, (2) a new understanding of the nature of the world; and (3) new forms of activity for changes in awareness. In the dimensions under discussion, the process of recently locating the element of the sacred in the profane sphere and the resacralisation of nature clearly emerges. In the conclusions we also consider to what extent the formative new spirituality on the ecological trait can help  to  popularise the  sustainable development idea within the framework of changing the religiousness of man at the start of the twenty-first century. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Polish Planners&#x2019; Attitudes Towards Citizen Participation</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2133968</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1885343&#x22;&#x3E;&#x141;ukasz Damurski&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;In the Polish spatial-planning system, planners are situated between the citizens, developers, local authorities and non-governmental organizations. Such a unique position gives them an opportunity to promote and stimulate the cooperation between the most important local players in order to reach constant and sustainable development of a given territorial unit. A question arises here: how does citizen participation look in practice? This paper looks for the answer by presenting selected findings of a survey conducted with Polish planners in 2010. The results suggest that planners are aware of the need for public involvement in the planning process though  they have some doubts about the real effects of such involvement. The planning practice proves that citizens first of all require satisfaction of their private interests, local authorities care mainly about the current political advantages and the planners lack the power and appropriate knowledge to conduct the public consultation process. The survey points to the need for improvement of the quality of the citizen participation in Poland. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Selecting Sustainability Indicators for Local Community &#x2013; Case Study of Milan&#xF3;wek Municipality, Poland</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2133977</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1509114&#x22;&#x3E;Ma&#x142;gorzata Grodzinska-Jurczak&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1885340&#x22;&#x3E;Justyna Gutowska&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1885910&#x22;&#x3E;Jerzy &#x15A;leszy&#x144;ski&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;Actions for sustainable development at the local community level are the key elements of Agenda 21 but they also prove to be a difficult challenge. The governance of this process needs sustainability indicators to assess changes in local socio-economic and environmental systems to date. This article presents results of research on the local sustainable development assessment in Milan&#x26;#xF3;wek Municipality in Poland. This is an attempt to use a mixed, reductionist-participatory approach to selecting sustainability indicators for one local community in Poland. The paper shows how to develop and use, at the time of broad theoretical debate on implementation of sustainable development strategies, a set of indicators helping us to shape the development strategy of a municipality to fully satisfy its requirements. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>The &#x3C;I&#x3E;Book of Esther&#x3C;/I&#x3E;: Lessons in Leadership</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134986</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=447157&#x22;&#x3E;Linda Weiser Friedman&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=638928&#x22;&#x3E;Hershey H. Friedman&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;This paper examines the Book of Esther, deriving important insights about a variety of approaches to leadership that can be applied to today&#x26;#x2018;s crisis in leadership. Esther was a Queen of Persia approximately 2,500 years ago. In reviewing the leadership styles of three characters from this biblical story, the Book of Esther is seen to contain fascinating examples and counterexamples of effective leadership. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Talmud as a Business Guide</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134472</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=638928&#x22;&#x3E;Hershey H. Friedman&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;Purpose: There is a great deal of interest in discovering the secrets of business success according to the Talmud. This interest is satisfied in the present paper by listing and explaining some principles, stories, and cases from the Talmud.  Approach: The topic is approached in the manner of analysis of the Talmud as a business guide and as a set of stories and cases (part seven).  Findings: Some of the Talmudic sages were indeed quite wealthy (introduction). This paper demonstrates that the Talmudic approach to becoming wealthy (part two) involves respecting hard work, leading an ethical life, being charitable, treating employees well, going beyond the strict requirements of the law, and caring for others (parts three to six).  Implications: There are some indirect (conceptual) and some direct (in terms of principles and cases) implications of the Talmud as a business guide (as shown in part seven).  Methodology: Conceptual approach with addition of some Talmud stories as case studies. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Impact of Best Practices of Sustainability on Quality of Management: An Investigation at Brazilian Capital Markets</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2135129</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=71366&#x22;&#x3E;Jean E. Harris&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1332098&#x22;&#x3E;Walter Leal Filho&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1835176&#x22;&#x3E;Valdir de Jesus Lameira&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1837863&#x22;&#x3E;Walter Lee Ness Jr.&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1840317&#x22;&#x3E;Osvaldo Quelhas&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1840320&#x22;&#x3E;Roberto Pereira&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;The study of the relationship between best practices of sustainability and quality of management investigates one of the most relevant and topical issues involving researchers and professionals. For this investigation, a representative sample of 205 Brazilian companies was selected, covering the period from 2005 to 2009 to test for a possible relationship between participation in a sustainability index, an indicator of best practices of sustainability and indicators of the quality of management. After applying different econometric methods, it was possible to confirm the hypothesis that best practices of sustainability are associated with better performance, less risk and higher market value. Moreover, best practices of sustainability impact the value of companies directly and indirectly through the mediating variables of performance and risk. Finally, possible determinants of the quality of practices of sustainability are associated (1) with market values in a positive way and (2) with operating leverage, return on assets (ROA) and volatility in a negative way. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Economic Ownership of Special Purpose Entities: Applying Economic Theory to the Off-Balance-Sheet Problem</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134960</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1749753&#x22;&#x3E;Corinna Ewelt-Knauer&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;Special purpose entities (SPEs) are often used to remove unfavorable assets and liabilities from balance sheets. As a result, consolidated financial statements do not provide a true and fair view of the financial situation of the reporting entity and thus fail their intended aim of information usefulness. This paper presents an alternative approach for determining the economic owner of an SPE by analyzing the special characteristics of SPEs beyond the background of contract theory and the property rights theory (step 1). The presumption of economic ownership is validated based on transaction cost theory in a second step. The effectiveness of the concept developed is demonstrated by using different examples of typical SPE structures and by comparing the proposed concept to the regulations of IFRS 10. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>IFRS or IFRS-Based Domestic Standards: Implications for China&#x2019;s Future Accounting Reforms</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134519</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1640937&#x22;&#x3E;Dr. Muhammad Umar Draz&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;People&#x26;#x2019;s Republic of China has a long history of accounting and its reforms. This study focuses on suggesting the criterion of China&#x26;#x2019;s future accounting reforms i.e. whether those reforms should be based on the domestic standards or in compliance to the IASB&#x26;#x2019;s requirements? Binary choice model has been used in the analysis; the results indicate that the Chinese accounting reforms are significantly associated with the internal and external factors. In the light of statistical findings, environmental determinism theory and regulatory influence of the Chinese government on its accounting system, this study proposes that China should consider its domestic needs and convergence with the IFRS simultaneously while introducing the future accounting reforms. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Moral Development in Accounting Education: Education, Ethics and Charity Disclosures</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134135</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1788698&#x22;&#x3E;Samuel T. Tan&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;I examine whether accounting education is associated with better accounting decisions in the context of charity accounting disclosures, and the extent to which this is facilitated by moral development. Prior literature suggests that the information needs of donors have generally not been met by NPOs, and that while the charity sector is significant in size, growth and importance internationally, recent scandals may reflect failures of governance and accountability, the discharge of which should involve the disclosure of decision-useful information to stakeholders. I examine education as a solution to this problem, hypothesizing that a student that has undertaken more general or accounting education should make charity disclosure recommendations that better reflect that donor relevance of the disclosures. Additionally, I test the extent to which this is facilitated by moral development, motivated by arguments from prior literature that accounting disclosure decisions fall within the domain of ethics and that education should incorporate moral development.The hypotheses will be examined using data collected from a sample of students from Singapore; future versions of the paper will include the findings from the data and corresponding discussion and analysis. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Effect of Board Characteristics and Audit Committee Existence on Earnings Quality of Indonesian State-Owned Enterprises</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2135051</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1692964&#x22;&#x3E;Ancella Anitawati Hermawan&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1886036&#x22;&#x3E;Galuh Nur Adinda&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;The objective of this research is to determine the effect of Board of Commissioners characteristics which is assessed by number or size of, level of independence of, and amount of remuneration received by the Board of Commissioners on earning&#x26;#x2019;s quality of Indonesia&#x26;#x2019;s State-Owned Enterprises (&#x26;#x201C;SOE&#x26;#x201D;). The objective of this research is also to determine whether the existence of Audit Comittee has significant effect on the earnings quality of the SOE. Hypotheses testing are done by using a multiple regression model with 111 sample of State-Owned Enterprises whose majority share is owned by the state during 2009 dan 2010. The results provide empirical evidence that independency of Board of Commissioners increases the SOE earnings quality, meanwhile the other Board characteristics and the existence of Audit Committee has no significant effect on the SOE earnings quality. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Heterogeneous Wage Effects of Apprenticeship Training</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134691</link>
<description>Paywalled paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=101422&#x22;&#x3E;Thomas Zwick&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1885930&#x22;&#x3E;Kathrin Goggel&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;The relatively small average wage effects of employer and occupation changes after apprenticeship training mask large differences between occupation groups and apprentices with different schooling backgrounds. People who change employer and occupation within industrial occupations enjoy large wage advantages, whereas apprentices in commerce and trading occupations, as well as in construction and crafts occupations, face wage losses from an occupation change. The differences between the firms that provide the apprenticeship training are found to be small or insignificant. In this paper, we reconcile the differences between previous findings by comparing and replicating the empirical estimation strategies used. This demonstrates that selectivity in occupations and changes, unobserved heterogeneity between occupations, and sample selection do matter. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>An Empirical Investigation on HRD Climate and Knowledge Management Practices in Veterinary Sector in Assam</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134154</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1521080&#x22;&#x3E;Arup Barman&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1885885&#x22;&#x3E;Krishna Rani Nath&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;The present study focuses knowledge management in veterinary sector offices in Assam. It attempts to investigate the relationship of HRD Climate with gender, working place, working levels (position), unit/section and age of respondents and the relationship of KMP with gender, working place, working levels (position), unit/section and age of respondents separately the field of veterinarians in Assam. No better area of study than the relationship between HRD Climate and KMP in veterinarians field in which humans and veterinary technology can come together and can enhance the sustainable development of veterinary profession and livestock. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>The &#x3C;I&#x3E;Book of Esther&#x3C;/I&#x3E;: Lessons in Leadership</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134986</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=447157&#x22;&#x3E;Linda Weiser Friedman&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=638928&#x22;&#x3E;Hershey H. Friedman&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;This paper examines the Book of Esther, deriving important insights about a variety of approaches to leadership that can be applied to today&#x26;#x2018;s crisis in leadership. Esther was a Queen of Persia approximately 2,500 years ago. In reviewing the leadership styles of three characters from this biblical story, the Book of Esther is seen to contain fascinating examples and counterexamples of effective leadership. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Using &#x27;Opposing Responses&#x27; and Relative Performance to Distinguish Empirically Among Alternative Models of Promotions</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134362</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=389873&#x22;&#x3E;Jed DeVaro&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;Applying a simultaneous-equations estimation approach that accounts for both worker and firm behavior, I show that classic tournaments, market-based tournaments, and performance standards models can be empirically distinguished when promotions induce worker effort. I also show that market-based tournaments with effort choices can be distinguished from those with human capital investments. A key insight is that an empirical test can be based on the &#x26;#x201C;opposing responses&#x26;#x201D; property whereby workers and firms adjust their choice variables in opposite directions when the stochastic component of worker performance changes. Finally, I propose a new approach &#x26;#x2013; also requiring simultaneous equations &#x26;#x2013; for empirically distinguishing between classic tournaments and market-based tournaments with human capital investments, showing that the two models differ in their predictions regarding the average wage between job levels. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>