<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://www.dailyssrn.com">
<title>DailySSRN - E</title>
<link>http://www.dailyssrn.com</link>
<description>Summary of new papers published on SSRN over the last day</description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>publisher person</dc:publisher>
<syn:updateBase>2012-08-01T00:00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134693" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134598" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134685" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134822" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134685" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134983" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2135241" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
</channel>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134693">
<title>Envy and Inequality</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134693</link>
<description>Paywalled paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=53780&#x22;&#x3E;Ngo Van Long&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1885744&#x22;&#x3E;Francisco Alvarez&#x2010;Cuadrado&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;We present an overlapping generations economy, populated by heterogeneous agents who care about both consumption relative to others and the bequest they leave to their offspring. We show that saving and bequest rates vary across the income distribution, and we obtain several interesting results. First, envy reduces the steady&#x26;#x2010;state capital stock and increases the degree of inequality in consumption, capital ownership, and bequests. Second, if the bequest motive is sufficiently strong the equalizing effect of bequests disappears. Third, income inequality for a given cohort increases with age. Fourth, the distribution of inherited wealth becomes more unequal than that of wealth in general. Fifth, economic position becomes more persistent across generations. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134598">
<title>Barriers to Technological Adoption in Spain and Portugal</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134598</link>
<description>Abstract only by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1416&#x22;&#x3E;Steven P. Cassou&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1885692&#x22;&#x3E;Emanuel Xavier de Oliveira&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;Since 1945, both Spain and Portugal have experienced significant market transformations. These countries were both led by dictators for many years until the mid 1970s when each moved toward more democratic governments and more open markets. As a result, each experienced significant changes in output with Spain&#x26;#x2019;s becoming a model for proper market based transformations. Although Portugal&#x26;#x2019;s transformation has been less impressive it experienced improvements too. This paper uses a Parente and Prescott (J Polit Econ 102(2), 298-321, 1994; 2000) type model to investigate the recent transformations in each of these countries and quantify the extent to which barriers to technological adoption may have played for these two development experiences. Our results indicate that from 1945 to 2003 these barriers have fallen considerably but remain high, and are somewhat higher in Portugal than in Spain. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134685">
<title>The Role of Central Bank Transparency for Guiding Private Sector Forecasts</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134685</link>
<description>Paywalled paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=952&#x22;&#x3E;Sylvester C. W. Eijffinger&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=203739&#x22;&#x3E;Michael Ehrmann&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=335955&#x22;&#x3E;Marcel Fratzscher&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134822">
<title>Estimation of the Investment Function in Sudan (1979-2008)</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134822</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1389026&#x22;&#x3E;Issam A.W. Mohamed&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;Most developing and underdeveloped countries beside Sudan suffer from low levels of income in addition to the low savings that are result from the lack of sophisticatd savings channels. Hence, investments depend on the individuals&#x26;#x27; abilities on savings where they are major motivating vehicle for economic activity due to its direct correlation with capital accumulation process that increases the productive capacity for the national economy and help to create job opportunities and achieving economic development. Subsequently, the importance of the investment comes from the effective role that can be practiced on the national product. Currently, Sudan endures severe economic crisis which the degeneration of its economic sectors, subsequent deteriorating productivity and diminishing revenues specially after the secession of the Southern region and loss of more than 75% of oil resources. The needs for investments escalate to revive its ability to survive, without that can be mission impossible. This study aims at explaining the impact of influencing factors on the investment function in the Sudan. An econometric model is formulated, assuming that there is a causal relationship between investment and influential factors represented. The results show there is a positive relationship between investment and Gross Domestic Products (GDP), while there is a negative relationship between inflation rate and finance cost on investment. The study concluded that there is significant effect of the inflation rate and finance cost. However, there are other factors that may have negative impacts on investments which can vary from administrative complications to corruption that are rife and probably entrenched in the system. From the above mentioned results the study recommends that it is necessary to extend the analysis to include other variables with significant effect on investment such as imports, national income, and government expenditure to attain a model that can be used for investment anticipation in the coming years. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134685">
<title>The Role of Central Bank Transparency for Guiding Private Sector Forecasts</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134685</link>
<description>Paywalled paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=952&#x22;&#x3E;Sylvester C. W. Eijffinger&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=203739&#x22;&#x3E;Michael Ehrmann&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  and &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=335955&#x22;&#x3E;Marcel Fratzscher&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;</description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134983">
<title>Designing Monetary Policy Committees</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2134983</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=200471&#x22;&#x3E;Volker Hahn&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;We integrate a monetary policy committee into a New Keynesian model to assess the consequences of the committee&#x26;#x2019;s institutional characteristics for welfare. First, we prove that uncertainty about the committee&#x26;#x2019;s future composition may be desirable. Second, we show that longer terms of central bankers lead to more effective output stabilization at the expense of higher inflation variability. Third, larger committees allow for more efficient stabilization of both output and inflation, provided that the pool of candidates is sufficiently diverse. Finally, longer terms induce the government to appoint more conservative central bankers, which is conducive to welfare. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2135241">
<title>LIBOR or LIEBOR: The Challenge of Ethics and Education</title>
<link>http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2135241</link>
<description>Free paper by &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/cf_dev/AbsByAuth.cfm?per_id=1039977&#x22;&#x3E;Mohammad Omar Farooq&#x3C;/a&#x3E;  last revised on 2012-08-23
&#x3C;p&#x3E;Abstract:
&#x3C;br&#x3E;Recent scandal involuding manipulation of LIBOR has exposed some serious issues regarding ethics and business ethics education. This essay explores the relevant issues, especially as it might relate to Islamic finance. </description>
<dc:date>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 05:17:45 -0500</dc:date>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>